<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>His Majesties gracious answer to the letter direct from the Privy Council of this his antient kingdom of Scotland, in the present juncture of affairs, is as follows</title>
            <author>James II, King of England, 1633-1701.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24975</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">31355293</idno>
  <idno type="VID">205885</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240893122</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing J185</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">31355293</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24975)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 205885)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1740:43)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>His Majesties gracious answer to the letter direct from the Privy Council of this his antient kingdom of Scotland, in the present juncture of affairs, is as follows</title>
                  <author>James II, King of England, 1633-1701.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the heir of Andrew Anderson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1688.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Given at Our Court at Whitehall, the 6th day of October, 1688, And of Our Reign the Fourth Year. By His Majesties Command, Melfort."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Revolution of 1688.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  History --  Revolution of 1688.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:205885:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>James II's arms</figDesc>
                  <head>I R</head>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure>
               <hi>His</hi> MAJESTIES <hi>Gracious Answer to the Letter Direct from the Privy Council of this His Antient Kingdom of</hi> Scotland, <hi>in the present Juncture of Affairs, is as follows,</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>JAMES</hi> REX,</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">R</seg>Ight Trusty, and Right well-beloved Cousin and Councellor, Right Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sty, and Right well-beloved Councellors, Right Trusty and entirely belov<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Cousins and Councellors, Right Trusty, and Right well-beloved Cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sins and Councellors, Right Trusty and well-beloved Cousins and Councel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lors, Right Trusty and well-beloved Councellors, and Trusty and well-be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loved Councellors, VVe Greet you well. In your Letter of the 3<seg rend="sup">d</seg> of <hi>Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tober,</hi> VVe received the satisfactory Account of your Proceedings there, and the hearty Offers of your Assistance with your Lives and Fortunes, against Our Enemies, for which VVe return you Our hearty Thanks, and do renew Our assurance to you of Our Royal Favour, and that VVe shall never be unmindful of the Faithfulness and Loyalty of that Our Ancient Kingdom, manifested to Us on this Occasion, when We are so unjustly Attack't by Forreign Enemies; and when it shall please GOD (which VVe hope shall be quickly) to give Us the victory over Our Enemies, both you in particular, and Our Ancient People in general, shall feel the Gracious Effects of Our Royal Favour. VVe have thought fit, for Our Service, and for your Peace and Quiet, that such, as you have just reason to suspect of ill Designs against the Peace of Our Government, may be secured by Imprison<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or otherways, as you shall think fit: And because VVe have taken Our standing Forces from that Kingdom, and that the Levying of Men, Foot or Horse, may be for the well of Our Service, We leave to you, to raise such as you shall think fit, and to augment Our Garisons, as you shall find convenient. And We do hereby Authorize and Require you to give Commissions to such Officers of Militia, as you shall judge proper; And like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, to appoint Officers over the Heretors, as you shall judge fit: For doing all which, this shall be your Warrant: And so We bid you heartily Farewell.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at Our Court at</hi> Whitehall, <date>
                     <hi>the</hi> 6<seg rend="sup">th</seg>
                     <hi>day of</hi> October, 1688, <hi>And of Our Reign the Fourth Year,</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>By His <hi>Majesties</hi> Command, <hi>MELFORT.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the Heir of <hi>Andrew Anderson,</hi> Printer to His most Sacred <hi>Majesty,</hi> 1688.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>